<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../xslt/element.xslt"?>
<element number="eDispatch.05"  minOccurs="0"  maxOccurs="1"  dataTypeName="DispatchPriority"  isNillable="No">
<name>Dispatch Priority (Patient Acuity)</name>
<national>No</national>
<state>No</state>
<definition>The actual, apparent, or potential acuity of the patient’s condition as determined through information obtained during the EMD process.</definition>
<v2Number></v2Number>
<usage>Optional</usage>
<performanceMeasuresGroup></performanceMeasuresGroup>
<v3Comment>The use of priority and acuity values vary by EMS agency.  Some systems may utilize fewer than four priority levels and some more.  The use of four priority levels is to capture the majority and allow for the inclusion of the NHTSA National EMS Core Content definitions for patient acuity, specifically: Critical, Emergent, and Lower Acuity.
<br/><br/>
For EMS Agencies and CAD / EMD systems utilizing Alpha-Echo, Omega levels for determining the priority level for dispatch of the EMS unit, the recommended mapping is:
<br/><br/>
<table cellpadding="2px" cellspacing="0px" border="1px">
<tr>
<td>Echo = Priority 1</td><td>Charlie = Priority 2</td><td>Alpha = Priority 3</td>
</tr><tr>
<td>Delta = Priority 1</td><td>Bravo = Priority 2</td><td>Omega = Priority 4</td>
</tr></table>
<br/>
<br/>Priority 1 is typically an emergent (lights and sirens) response
<br/>Priority 2 is typically an emergent response without the use lights and sirens
<br/>Priority 3 is typically a non-emergent response for nursing home, hospital-to-hospital transfers, etc.
<br/>Priority 4 is typically a scheduled response (scheduled  transfer) or standby event
<br/><br/>
Definitions related to “Critical, Emergent, and Lower Acuity” can be found in the National EMS Core Content document from NHTSA EMS (DOT HS 809-898 July 2005) at 
<br/>http://www.nhtsa.gov/people/injury/ems/emscorecontent/images/EMSCoreContent.pdf</v3Comment>
<v3Changes></v3Changes>
<restrictions>
  <DispatchPriority baseType="string">
    <facet name="enumeration" value="2305001" annotation="Priority 1 (Critical)"/>
    <facet name="enumeration" value="2305003" annotation="Priority 2 (Emergent)"/>
    <facet name="enumeration" value="2305005" annotation="Priority 3 (Lower Acuity)"/>
    <facet name="enumeration" value="2305007" annotation="Priority 4 (Non-Acute [e.g. Scheduled Transfer  or Standby])"/>
  </DispatchPriority>
</restrictions>
</element>
